Mohamed Moataz

Software Engineer

Giza, Egypt

+20 100 858 1523

G:<u>imohammedmoataz@gmail</u>

W:https://mohammed-moata z.vercel.app/

SUMMARY

Resourceful **software engineer** with both front-end and back-end development experience. Smart and consistently educated designer of user interactions on sound and user-friendly websites and databases. Proven troubleshooting with a solid grounding in data-driven concepts and applications.

EXPERIENCE

Catch Code, Egypt — *Software Engineer*

Jun 2023 - Oct 2023

- Augmented with the backend team to develop APIs using Node.JS
- Collaborated to develop the desktop application using JavaFX.
- Analyzed, prioritized, and problem-solved several tasks concurrently with minimum supervision.

CBMIS, Remotely—Software Engineer Trainee

Jun 2022 - Jan 2023

- Learned new emerging technologies and techniques.
- Analyzed, prioritized, and problem-solved several tasks.

EDUCATION

Faculty of Computers and Artificial Intelligence Helwan University, Cairo —Very Good

September 2019 - July 2023.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Concepts

OOP / Data Structures / Design Patterns / Restful APIs / GraphQL

Development

BlockChain / Node.JS / React.JS

CONTACTS

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammed-moataz/

GitHub:

https://github.com/Mohamm edMoataz

SKILLS

Adaptability.

Fast learning.

Teamwork.

Good Listener.

CERTIFICATIONS

<u>Google IT Support</u>, Google

Dec 2022

Agile Scrum, ODC

Sep 2022

ITI Java Spring Developer, ITI

Sep 2022

Web Design, NTI

Aug 2022

Google Project Management Specialization, Google

Jun 2022

Data Storage

MySQL / MongoDB

Tools

Docker / Git / Swagger / Trello

LANGUAGES

Arabic

English

PROJECTS

https://mohammed-moataz.vercel.app/projects

MobiCare — Node.JS, Truffle, MySQL, Firebase, and Flutter

Dec 2022 - June 2023

- Responsible for delivering the project in an incremental way.
- Responsible for Managing and prioritizing the product backlog.
- Responsible for the blockchain feature.
- Participated with the backend team to build Rest APIs.
- Participated with the Flutter team to integrate Blockchain.

Pulse App — Flutter, Firebase, and IoT

Feb 2022 - Mar 2023

- Augmented with a team of 6 to develop a mobile app for the 2022
 Google Solution Challenge, and we could reach the TOP 10 in the MENA region.
- Collaborated to develop a user interface within the mobile application using **Flutter** with **MVVM** architecture pattern.

VOLUNTEERING

Google Developers Student Club - Helwan University

2022 Technical Head.

- Flutter Instructor.
- Responsible for How-To workshops.

2021 Technical Core Team Member.

- Data Structures Instructor.

Online - Helwan University

2022 Vice president.

2019 Media team member.